Finding Aid for the David P. Gamble papers LSC.1997
UCLA Library Special Collections
David P. Gamble papers
1920-2007
UCLA Library Special Collections
Gamble, David P.
LSC.1997
68 Linear Feet (54 record cartons, 32 document boxes, 3 flat boxes)
Anthropologist David P. Gamble was born in 1920 in Northern Ireland and passed away in California in 2011 after a long career of research and teaching. The collection contains a variety of material related to Gamble's more than six decades of work on The Gambia and its peoples. Copies of the anthropologist's publications on Gambian history, economics, languages, and cultures are included, along with many of the notes, maps, illustrations, primary sources, and secondary sources from which he generated these studies. Gamble's output was wide-ranging, but of special note are his contributions to the bibliography of The Gambia; the ethno-linguistic study of Wolof, Mandinka, and Fula; and the early history of the Gambia River region.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Collection acquired from David P. Gamble and Linda K. Salmon between 2011 and 2012.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID:9970019423606533
Biography/History
David P. Gamble was born in 1920 in Northern Ireland and passed away in California in 2011 after a long career of anthropological research and teaching. Completing his undergraduate studies at University College, London in 1941, Gamble spent several years assisting with archaeological and physical studies of highland communities in Northern Ireland. After a brief stint in the Royal Engineers, he joined the Colonial Administrative Service in 1944 in the Gold Coast (now Ghana), taking up posts in Tarkwa, Axim, and Sekondi. At that time, Gamble's academic supervisor Daryll Forde, who was then Director of the International African Institute, began conceiving a series of studies, later known as the Ethnographic Survey of Africa, which aimed to fill wide gaps in ethnographic knowledge of the continent. The Gambia was viewed as a site in need of research. Gamble's other mentor, economic anthropologist Raymond Firth, also conducted a survey of what was then British West Africa and came to the same conclusion. At Forde's and Firth's urging, Gamble conducted field research among Mandinka, Wolof, Jola, and Fula communities in The Gambia between 1946 and 1958, initially with the support of a Colonial Research Fellowship and later as a Research Officer under The Gambia Government. With a dissertation on the socioeconomic conditions of the Mandinka village Kerewan, Gamble earned his Ph.D. in anthropology from the University of London in 1958. The anthropologist returned to The Gambia for research numerous times between 1963 and 1986. Published in 1967, Gamble's The Wolof of Senegambia, Together with Notes on the Lebu and the Serer became a valuable addition to Forde's Ethnographic Survey. Among many other publications, Gamble produced a 52-volume series of studies on Gambian history, society, and culture, titled Gambian Studies (1977-2007). In 1999, as a culmination of his work on early Gambian history, Gamble edited a scholarly edition of The Discovery of River Gambra (1623) by Richard Jobson.
Gamble began his academic career with teaching and research appointments at the University of Edinburgh (1959-1963), San Francisco State College (1963-1965), Queen's University Belfast (1965-1966), and Njala University College in Sierra Leone (1966-1967). In 1967, he became Associate Professor of Anthropology at San Francisco State University, from which he retired as a tenured Professor in 1986. He remained Professor Emeritus there until his death in 2011.
Scope and Content
The collection contains original and secondary material related to Gamble's more than six decades of research on The Gambia and its peoples. This includes original notes, illustrations, maps, photographs, and correspondence produced during the anthropologist's extensive fieldwork among Mandinka, Wolof, Jola, and Fula communities in The Gambia. Copies of the anthropologist's publications on Gambian history, economics, languages, and cultures are included, along with many of the primary and secondary sources, including newspapers, photocopies of documents, books and periodicals, and government reports, from which he generated these studies. At the heart of Gamble's corpus of published work is his monumental 52-volume Gambian Studies series, a complete set of which is held in the collection. Gambian Studies is comprised of bibliographies of The Gambia; dictionaries and grammars of Wolof, Mandinka, and Fula languages; collections of folktales, stories, and proverbs; studies of historical sources; and general ethnographies of the country's people.
Gamble's research is topically wide-ranging and methodologically diverse, reflecting the influence of his mentors and his own eclectic expertise. Geographically, his work focuses on The Gambia, but extends to Senegal and Sierra Leone. Topics and issues covered include trade, agriculture, land tenure, law and legal systems, folklore, material culture, verbal and visual culture, language, life-cycle ceremonies, music, and the colonial encounter. Methods included mapping, census-taking, field observation, photography, sound recording, analysis of historical documents, and interviews. Gamble treated research projects iteratively, revisiting ideas and sources numerous times over the course of his career. Date ranges of accumulated research material can therefore be quite wide within a single subject area. Gamble's publications are, in many cases, present in both final and draft manuscript forms.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in twelve series by subject matter and type of material.
Series 1: Personal materials, 1920-2000
Series 2: Wolof research materials, 1920-2007
Series 3: Mandinka research materials, 1940-2006
Series 4: The Gambia research materials, 1920-2007
Series 5: Senegambian music, 1975-2004
Series 6: Photographs, 1920-2007
Subseries 6.1: Photo prints and negatives
Subseries 6.2: Photo clippings
Series 7: Fula research materials, 1920-2007
Series 8: Jola, Lebu, Serer, and Serahuli research materials, 1920-2007
Series 9: Sierra Leone / Temne research materials, 1920-2007
Series 10: Gambian Studies Series, 1976-2007
Series 11: Gambian newspapers and periodicals, ca. 1960-2004
Series 12: Books and theses, 1920-2007
Subseries 12.1: Theses, 1967-1994
Subseries 12.2: Books, 1920-2007
Related Material
Gamble's sound recordings and slide photographs, as well as his original collection indexes, are held in the UCLA Ethnomusicology Archive: David P. Gamble Collection (2011.08). Selected volumes of Gamble's Gambian Studies series are available for download through St. Mary's College of Maryland: http://www.smcm.edu/gambia/david_gamble.html.
- Series 1: Personal materials, 1920-2000
  Scope and Content
  This series is comprised of materials related to Gamble's early life, academic training, and teaching career. It includes his birth certificate, early family photographs, school and university certificates and diplomas, and references from his academic mentors. A variety of life history materials and documentation used in the writing of Gamble's 2002 autobiography, Gambian Research: the Anthropological Life of David P. Gamble, form a core part of this series. Representing his early academic training and his lifelong personal interest, Gamble's finished and unfinished research on the peoples of Northern Ireland is included here.
  Organization and Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Addresses and personal inventory, undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Birth certificate, 1920 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - British passports, 1939-1989 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - "Daily Life of a District Commissioner's Clerk", 1944-1945 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Dance certificates, 1964-1965 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Family photographs, 1920s (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Immigration documents, 1963-1984 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Inserts for Gamble dissertation, 1958 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - International drivers licenses, ca. 1955-1962 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Life history material (1 of 3), ca. 2000 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Life history material (2 of 3), ca. 2000 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Life history material (3 of 3), ca. 2000 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Life history material: "supporting documents", ca. 2000 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Northern Ireland articles, notes, certificates, ca. 1940 - 1970 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Northern Ireland map, undated (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Name files and correspondence, undated (Box 49)
  - Photocopies of articles by or about Gamble (1 of 2), undated (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Photocopies of articles by or about Gamble (2 of 2), undated (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Post-tenure review, San Francisco State University, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Retirement and SFSU miscellanea, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - School certificates, 1938 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - School and university exams and references, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Secondary and emeritus certificates, address book, manuscript of dissertation, 1936-1986 (Box 86)
  - University diplomas, 1941-1958 (Box 87)
- Series 2: Wolof research materials, 1920-2007
  This series is comprised of materials related to Gamble's study of Wolof society, culture, language, and history. It includes notes from Gamble's fieldwork in Wolof areas, books and periodicals, annotated photocopies of primary and secondary sources, as well as maps, illustrations, and diagrams generated in the course of research. Gamble's research on the Wolof is extensive and includes the early history of Goree Island (Senegal), Wolof folktales and proverbs, and Wolof language and linguistic history. These materials are the foundation of Gamble's publications on the Wolof, including The Wolof of Senegambia, Together with Notes on the Lebu and the Serer (1957); and Gambian Studies volumes 10A, 10B, 22, 25, 26, 27, 37, and 50, which include his Wolof-English dictionaries and grammars. Series includes materials in English, French, and Wolof.
  This series follows original order, as listed in Gamble's collection index.
  - Books, periodicals, dictionaries (1 of 5), undated (Box 17)
  - Books, periodicals, dictionaries (2 of 5), undated (Box 18)
  - Books, periodicals, dictionaries (3 of 5), undated (Box 19)
  - Books, periodicals, dictionaries (4 of 5), undated (Box 23)
  - Books, periodicals, dictionaries (5 of 5), undated (Box 24)
  - Goree: Manuscript, Gambian Studies 50, 1990-1992 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Goree: Articles and photocopies (1 of 3), 1990-1992 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Goree: Articles and photocopies (2 of 3), 1990 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Goree: Articles and photocopies (3 of 3), 1990-1992 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Goree: Manuscript, James Island by Winifred Galloway, 1990-1992 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Goree: Manuscript on John Hill by Pat Wilson, 1990-1992 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Goree: Notes, timeline, correspondence, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Goree: Photocopy of John Hill's diary and Wolof grammar (1 of 2), 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Goree: Photocopy of John Hill's diary and Wolof grammar (2 of 2), 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Goree: Maps and plans, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Goree: Photographs, postcards, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Goree: Correspondence with Pat Wilson and Akbar Muhammed, 1973-1975 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Goree: Typescript of John Hill's diary, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Goree: Transcript of Hill's Wolof grammar as read by Hassan Njie, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Goree: Notes from Pat Wilson and George Brooks, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Errata to Wolof dictionary, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Early manuscripts of Wolof-English Dictionary, 1958, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript of Wolof-English Dictionary (Gambian Studies 23), 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Working copy, Wolof-English Dictionary (Gambian Studies 23), 1993 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Typescript of "the Baha'i Faith", 1957 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript of Elementary Wolof Grammar", 1958 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Photocopies of Wolof books by Hannah Kilham and Rev. James Fieldhouse (19th century), 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Index cards of Wolof "borrowed words", undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Language material from old books, 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Photocopy of G. Mollien's Vocabulary de la langue lolofe [Wolof] (19th century), 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Excerpts of Wolof vocabulary by Geoffroy de Villeneuve (18th century), with notes, 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Photocopies of Goldberry and Corry vocabularies (19th century), 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - 17th century Wolof: photocopies and notes, 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Old [Wolof] words, 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Photocopies, notes, and typescript of "Barbot's Vocabularies" (17th century), and correspondence with P.E.H. Hair, 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Photocopy of Omarka's "Wolof Phonology and Morphology", 1994 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Grammar and syntax: French sources (Diagne, Malherbe, Kobes, Njie) (1 of 2), 1990 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Grammar and syntax: French sources (Diagne, Malherbe, Kobes, Njie) (2 of 2), 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Borrowings from Fula, Mandinka, 1970s, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Stories and vocabulary (typescripts), 1972, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Wolof and Serer language, 1974, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of articles on Wolof (Senegal), 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - New vocabulary, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Photocopies of Gambian Wolof articles, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Vocabulary: French and Senegalese sources, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - "Odds and ends" including correspondence with Harold Torrence and Tijan Sallah, 1990-1992, 2004 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Photocopies of material by Judith T. Irvine, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Banjul Wolof vocabulary: Reuben Lusack and Ida Ward material, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Up-river Wolof, including "Wolof Songs" by Keba Kadi Njai, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Orthography, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Duplicates of Wolof-English Dictionary and Elementary Grammar, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Elementary Wolof Grammar (duplicate), 1958 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Extracts from David Ames' field notes (history, childbirth/naming, marriage, funeral), 1970-1984 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Typescript of La Sénégambie by M. Jules Remy (circa 19th century), 1970-1984 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Documentary material pre-1800, 1974-1984 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Lisa Barlow and Gamble's transcription of Wolof tapes, 1970s, 1990-1992 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Senegambia Bibliography (including Serer and Lebu), undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Walter Pichl's material with typescript translated by Gamble and annotation of vocabulary, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Quotations from and references to Wolof scholarship, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Field notes: census, Upper Saalum, 1974-1980 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Field notes (Gamble, with notes by David Ames and Hassan Njai): childbirth, housing, trading, 1946 aerial photos, 1974-1980 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Documentary material 1800-1850, 1974-1984 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Documentary material 1851-1900, 1974-1984 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Documentary material 1901-1939, 1974-1984 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Documentary material 1940-1949 (book extracts and photocopies), 1977-1984 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Documentary material 1950-1959, 1977-1984 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Articles 1960-1965, 1977-1985 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Articles 1966-1969 (1 of 2), 1980-1985 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Articles 1966-1969 (2 of 2), 1980-1985 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Articles 1970-1979 (1 of 3), 1980-1985 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Articles 1970-1979 (2 of 3), 1980 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Articles 1970-1979 (3 of 3), 1980-1985 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Articles 1980s (1 of 3), 1985 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Articles 1980s (2 of 3), 1985 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Articles 1980s (3 of 3), 1985 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Articles 1990s-2000s, 2003 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Field notes on Njau/Upper Saalum (1 of 3), 1947-1965 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Field notes on Njau/Upper Saalum (2 of 3), 1947-1965 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Field notes on Njau/Upper Saalum (3 of 3), 1947-1965 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence regarding Family of Man article from Charles R. Fowkes, ed., 1975 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Corrections of survey for Wolof of Senegambia revision, 1957-1967 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Field notes from Hassan Njie (1968), 1974-1984 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Field notes on child rearing by Hassan Njie, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Chapter on Wolof, notes and comments for Gambian Studies 17, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Women: articles and excerpts including Grandmaison book and clippings from Amina, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Unpublished material (Cottingham, Charles, Ames), 1984 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Dress and jewelry, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Naming ceremony: notes/background material, 1984-1989 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Senegambia: 1990s documentary material (1 of 3), 1990-1999 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Senegambia: 1990s documentary material (2 of 3), 1990-1999 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Senegambia: 1990s documentary material (3 of 3), 1990-1999 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Maps and diagrams (1 of 4), circa 1947-1976 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Maps and diagrams (2 of 4), circa 1947-1976 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Maps and diagrams (3 of 4), circa 1947-1976 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Maps and diagrams (Njau) (4 of 4), 1947-1948 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - References, circa 1980s (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Extracts from books (1 of 2), circa 1980s (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Extracts from books (2 of 2), circa 1980s (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - "Residue" including typescript notes on Gambian Studies 17 (1985) by B.K. Sagnia, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Islam and Mouride/Muridiyya Brotherhood (1 of 2), circa 2003 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Islam and Mouride/Muridiyya Brotherhood (2 of 2), circa 2003 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - References on Ndiadiane Ndiaye (aka Njaja Njie), circa 1990s (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Unpublished material by Samba Diop: "Historical Genealogies...", circa 1990s (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Unpublished thesis by Samba Dip and CV and letter of recommendation by Gamble, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Summary of Wolof folktales for Kasteloot's book, 1987-1989 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Folktales (photocopies, notes, and extracts) (1 of 2), 1987-1989 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Folktales (photocopies, notes, and extracts) (2 of 2), 1987-1989 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Folktales and comparative material (Linda Salmon) (1 of 2), 1987-1989 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Folktales and comparative material (Linda Salmon) (2 of 2), 1987-1989 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Legends, manuscript and correspondence by Bonnie L. Wright, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Stories: "general notes/new material", 1990s (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Stories: supplementary material, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Gambia High School stories, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Gambian stories (non-Wolof school children), 1963 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Proverbs (notes, photocopies, extracts) (1 of 2), circa 1988-1990s (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Proverbs (notes, photocopies, extracts) (2 of 2), circa 1988-1990s (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Birago Diop (articles), undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Riddles, undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Photocopy of Diaeli by Andre Demaison (1931), circa 1986-1987 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Folktales, comparative material (1 of 2), circa 1986-1987 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Folktales, comparative material (2 of 2), circa 1986-1987 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Judith Bettelheim material on fanal and jonkonnu, circa 1987-1989 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Photocopies, notes, illustrations from books, circa 1987-1989 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, photocopies, postcards, circa 1987-1989 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Photo prints by Linda Salmon, 1974-1984 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Small photo prints by David Gamble, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Photo prints by David Gamble, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Small photo prints by David Gamble, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Autobiographies, stories, circa 1986-1989 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript of Verbal and Visual Expressions of Wolof Culture (Gambian Studies 22), 1988-1989 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers and extracts, circa 1982 (Box 88, Folder 2)
- Series 3: Mandinka research materials, 1940-2006
  This series is comprised of materials related to Gamble's study of Mandinka society, culture, language, and history. It includes notes from Gamble's fieldwork in Mandinka areas, books and periodicals, annotated photocopies of primary and secondary sources, as well as maps, illustrations, and diagrams generated in the course of research. Gamble's dissertation, "An Analysis of the Economic Conditions and Underlying Factors in a Gambian Mandinka Community," (1958) and his earlier publications for the Research Department of the Colonial Office are based on extended stays in the villages of Kerewan and Keneba during the late 1940s and early 1950s. His research in Mandinka country was largely sociological, economic, and linguistic, focused on the collection and analysis of census data, the observation and documentation of land use and agricultural practices, and the mapping of each village's physical layout and kinship structures, as well as on the compilation of Mandinka vocabulary and grammar. Later work turned to the study of Mandinka folklore and ceremonies. Gamble's colonial-era publications and later writings on the Mandinka (Gambian Studies volumes 2-9, 20-21, 34, and 49) are included in the collection. Series includes materials in English, French, and Mandinka.
  - Mandinka books (may also contain Serahuli and Wolof), undated (Box 32)
  - Mandinka dictionaries and grammars, undated (Box 34)
  - Kerewan: rainfall, agricultural techniques and activities, field notes, 1940s-1950s (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Kerewan: correspondence/crop yields, 1950s (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Kerewan: agriculture, 1946-1963 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Kerewan: miscellaneous notes on agriculture, circa 1948 (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Kerewan: census, 1956-1957 (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Kerewan: diary, marriage cases, circa 1948-1951 (Box 81, Folder 11)
  - Kerewan: plans, maps, diagrams, circa 1948 (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - Kerewan: residual material from thesis, circa 1946-1958 (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - Kerewan: old notes, draft reports, circa 1946-1947 (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - Kerewan: hungry season, new rice areas, 1956-1957 (Box 81, Folder 15)
  - Kerewan: land utilization, 1966 (Box 81, Folder 16)
  - Kerewan: notes from short visits, 1956-1958 (Box 81, Folder 17)
  - Kerewan: census data and analysis of sociological data, circa 1947-1950 (Box 81, Folder 18)
  - Kerewan: Kabilo (age set) structure, circa 1948 (Box 81, Folder 19)
  - Kerewan: economics- general, agriculture, 1946-1956 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Kerewan: people away, circa 1946-1956 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Kerewan: marriage/divorce, circa 1948-1949 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Kerewan: furnishing/equipment of houses, circa 1946-1956 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Kerewan: peoples' roles at ceremonies, circa 1948-1949 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Kerewan: notes on development, circa 1946-1956 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Kerewan: comments/review/correspondence regarding economic studies, circa 1949-1959 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Kerewan: data on trade/agriculture from provincial reports, 1930s-1940s (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Keneba: census of 1951 (1 of 2) (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Keneba: census of 1951 (2 of 2) (Box 82, Folder 10)